Maria is a history, drama, music film directed by Pablo Larraín.
Maria Callas, the world's greatest opera singer, lives the last days of her
life in 1970s Paris, as she confronts her identity and life.
Maria Callas, played by Angelina Jolie.
Ferruccio, played by Pierfrancesco Favino.
Bruna, played by Alba Rohrwacher.
Aristotle Onassis, played by Haluk Bilginer.
Mandrax, played by Kodi Smit-McPhee.
Jeffrey Tate, played by Stephen Ashfield.
Maria is a 2024 biographical psychological drama film directed
by Pablo Larraín and written by Steven Knight.
It is an international co-production between Italy,
Chile, Germany and the United States.
The film stars Angelina Jolie as opera singer Maria Callas, and follows the week
before her death in 1977 Paris, as she reflects on her life and career.
It also stars Pierfrancesco Favino, Alba Rohrwacher, Haluk Bilginer, Stephen
Ashfield, Valeria Golino, and Kodi Smit-McPhee in supporting roles.
It is the third film in Larraín's trilogy of iconic 20th-century
women, following Jackie (2016), and Spencer (2021).
The film premiered at the 81st Venice International Film Festival on August 29, 2024, where it competed for the Golden
Lion and received generally positive reviews from critics, who singled out Jolie's performance for praise.
It was released in select theaters in the United States on November
27, 2024, before streaming on Netflix on December 11.
It was theatrically released in Italy by 01 Distribution on January 1, 2025,
before its release in Germany by StudioCanal on February 6.
The film earned a nomination for Best Cinematography at the 97th Academy Awards, while Jolie was
nominated for Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Drama at the 82nd Golden Globe Awards.
The film explores themes of opera, paris, france, 1970s, surrealism, biography.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and mind_bending.